<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>Arcane Syntax: Posts tagged 'games'</title>
  <description>Arcane Syntax: Posts tagged 'games'</description>
  <link>http://jarcane.github.com/tags/games.html</link>
  <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 10:53:59 FLE Daylight Time</lastBuildDate>
  <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 10:53:59 FLE Daylight Time</pubDate>
  <ttl>1800</ttl>
  <item>
   <title>Apologizing for exuberance</title>
   <link>http://jarcane.github.com/blog/2014/09/19/apologizing-for-exuberance.html</link>
   <guid>urn:http-jarcane-github-com:-blog-2014-09-19-apologizing-for-exuberance-html</guid>
   <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 10:53:59 FLE Daylight Time</pubDate>
   <description>&lt;html&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after some further consideration, I think I am not really the person to reinvent the internet filter. I have a lot of learning to do before I could possibly tackle something like that in anything like a useful manner. It&amp;rsquo;s possible I could hack together a pretty simple word-frequency model, but I&amp;rsquo;m not at all certain I could really go beyond that; I&amp;rsquo;m not an AI programmer, nor do I have any experience with natural language processing. My experience so far has mostly been with basic systems programming and game design. It&amp;rsquo;s probable I&amp;rsquo;ll return to the problem in the distant future, but for right now I think it&amp;rsquo;s best I leave such a task to more capable hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just get frustrated. I feel like I actually want to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; something about the shit that&amp;rsquo;s going on, besides just spreading the word about it and condemning it. That is, to me, literally the least I can do. Hell, if I &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; do that, I&amp;rsquo;d think rather ill of myself, frankly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am merely a writer, ultimately, be it in code, in prose, or in games. And as I said before, when all the tools you have are words, but the jackals have not ears to hear or eyes to read those words, it can feel like a bit of a useless talent. Instead perhaps the best I can do is, if not contributing to the fight for equality necessarily, at least to the fight for a better class of game that speaks to broader themes and more inclusive worlds than more manshoots and bald-man-saves-the-world games. Recent events have really done havoc to my motivation and enthusiasm for gaming; but maybe if I can write something I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; enthusiastic about, it might come back. If good writing and creativity are &amp;ldquo;killing games&amp;rdquo;, then maybe I should take up the hatchet as well&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m curious what others think, especially those women who&amp;rsquo;re facing this mess. What can I do? Or even, &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; I be doing anything other than what I have been; after all, it&amp;rsquo;s your voice far more than mine that needs to be heard right now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>